Beth Deutmeyer

Teacher | Musician | Full-stack web developer Word game enthusiast | Crocheter Puzzle lover | Problem solver | Mom 205 Christopher Ave, Waukee, IA 50263 bethdeutmeyer@gmail.com | (641) 373-2232 LinkedIn | GitHub | Project Portfolio

Coding Skills:

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | SQL | GraphQL | MERN (Mongo.db, Express.js, React, Node.js)

Professional Summary

I am an experienced teacher and accomplished musician with additional training in web development. After limiting myself to part-time work for several years in order to raise my children at home, I am looking to expand my career. Responsible, highly educated, and versatile, I am eager to branch out into new arenas, further my skills, and leverage my abilities in interesting and challenging ways.

Education

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development

Northwestern University Coding Boot Camp | December 2023

Doctor of Musical Arts | University of Nebraska-Lincoln | May 2012 Doctoral document: Performing Editions of Handel Cantatas - DigitalCommons

Master of Music | University of Nebraska-Lincoln | May 2009

Bachelor of Music | Iowa State University | May 2006

Experience

Voice instructor | Self-employed, private studio | Waukee, IA | May 2006 - Present

- Provide individual instruction to students in vocal technique and artistry
- Handle all communications, scheduling, and financial records
- Create and enforce studio policies
- Maintain a full student roster and wait list

Freelance Proofreader | Perfection Learning | Clive, IA | July 2024 - Present

- Check assigned texts for spelling and grammatical errors
- Ensure documents adhere to the Perfection Learning Style Guide
- Audit document layout
- Complete projects accurately and on time

Voice instructor

School for Music Vocations at Southwestern Community College | Creston, IA | August 2022 - May 2023 Urbandale High School | Urbandale, IA | October 2019 - April 2023

Theodore Roosevelt High School | Des Moines, IA | April 2022 - April 2023

Drake University | Des Moines, IA | August 2014 - May 2018

Iowa State University | Ames, IA | August 2013 - December 2013 (sabbatical replacement)

- Provide individual instruction to students in vocal technique and artistry
- Outline and enforce studio expectations
- Assess performance and submit grades (where applicable)